Into the Woods is a drama, music, fantasy film directed by James Lapine.
In a woods filled with magic and fairy tale characters, a baker and his wife set out
to end the curse put on them by their neighbor, a spiteful witch.
Witch, played by Bernadette Peters.
Baker, played by Chip Zien.
Baker's Wife, played by Joanna Gleason.
Narrator/Mysterious Man, played by Tom Aldredge.
Cinderella's Prince/Wolf, played by Robert Westenberg.
Cinderella, played by Kim Crosby.
Into the Woods is a 2014 American musical fantasy film directed by Rob Marshall, with a screenplay by
James Lapine based on his and Stephen Sondheim's 1987 Broadway musical of the same name.
Produced by Walt Disney Pictures, it features an ensemble cast that includes Meryl Streep, Emily Blunt,
James Corden, Anna Kendrick, Chris Pine, Tracey Ullman, Christine Baranski, and Johnny Depp.
The film is centered on a childless couple who set out to end a curse placed on them by a vengeful
witch, and the characters are forced to experience the consequences of their actions.
It is inspired by the Grimm Brothers' fairy-tales of "Little Red Riding
Hood", "Cinderella", "Jack and the Beanstalk", and "Rapunzel".
After several unsuccessful attempts by other studios and producers to adapt the musical to film, Disney announced in
2012 that it was producing an adaptation, with Marshall directing and John DeLuca serving as producer.
Principal photography commenced in September 2013, and took place entirely in
the United Kingdom, including at Shepperton Studios in London.
Into the Woods had its world premiere in New York City on December 8, 2014, and was
released theatrically in the United States on December 25, 2014.
It was commercially successful and received generally positive reviews, receiving praise for its acting performances (particularly
Streep's and Blunt's), visual style, production values, and musical numbers, and criticism for its tone in the final act.
Into the Woods was named one of the top-eleven best films of 2014 by the American Film Institute; the film received three Academy Award nominations, including
a Best Supporting Actress nomination for Streep, and three Golden Globe Award nominations, including Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of princess, fairy tale,
prince, little red riding hood, musical.
The tone is emotional.